Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is finally Masked Yaiba! Inside the costume is an incident!
!اليوم ظهور ليايبا المقنّع أخيراً! يمكنك رؤية حادثة داخل التنكّر
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ دماغه لبالغ
Oh? You're eating out today, Conan-kun?
ماذا؟ ستأكل في الخارج اليوم يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah, I'm meeting them in front of this shrine at 6:00.
أجل، سألتقيهما أمام هذا الضريح عند السادسة
You're so lucky. Is it eel?
يا لحظّك، أهو أنقليس؟
No, I think a good curry restaurant opened up near here.
كلا، أظن أنّ مطعم كاري لذيذ اُفتتح بالجوار
I love curry!
!أنا أحبّ الكاري
Let's eat, too!
!لنأكل أيضاً
I want a jumbo fried shrimp curry!
!أريد كاري قريدس مقليّ كبير
Geez, you guys...
...أنتم
The Laser Police!
!شرطة الليزر
Laser Police?
شرطة الليزر؟
The police squad in Masked Yaiba!
!فرقة الشرطة في يايبا المقنّع
I love Masked Yaiba!
!أنا أحبّ يايبا المقنّع
Does this mean they're filming Masked Yaiba at this shrine?!
أيمكن أنّكم تصوّرون يايبا المقنّع في هذا الضريح؟
Oh, no, it's not like that...
...كلا، ليس الأمر هكذا
This gun's so cool!
!هذا المسدّس رائع
Don't touch that!
!لا تلمسه
Sorry!
آسف
This gun is important for fighting monsters, so only I can touch it.
،هذا المسدّس مهمٌ لقتال الوحوش لذا لا يمكن أن أترك أحداً يلمسه
Bye!
!إلى اللقاء
What's the big deal?
ما المشكلة لو لمسته قليلاً؟
Conan-kun! Been waiting long?
كونان-كن، هل انتظرتَ طويلاً؟
No, I just got here.
كلا، وصلت لتويّ
What's with you guys?
ما خطبكم؟
They want to eat curry with us!
قالوا أنّهم يريدون أكل الكاري معنا
What?!
!ماذا؟
Oh, come on! The more the merrier!
أين المشكلة؟ سيكون ألذّ لو أكلنا معاً
And who's gonna pay for 'em?
ومن سيدفع؟
You.
أنت يا أبي
Oh, but call your moms first, so they won't worry!
لكن عليكم الاتّصال بأمّهاتكم أوّلاً كيلا يقلقن عليكم
Okay!
!حسناً
Geez!
يا إلهي
What kind of parents are they, all saying, "That would be great!"?!
أيّ جماعة آباء يردّون بـ "نتركهم في عهدتك!"؟
Look!
انظروا
It's Masked Yaiba!
!يايبا المقنّع
Yaiba Kick!
!ركلة يايبا
Awesome! Awesome!
!مذهل! مذهل
So cool!
!رائع جدّاً
This is like a dream!
!كأنّي أحلم
First the Laser Police, and now Masked Yaiba? What's with today?
شرطة الليزر، ثمّ يايبا المقنّع بعدها؟ ما الذي يجري اليوم بالضبط؟
Oh! Aren't you Mori Kogoro-san, the great detective?!
ماذا؟ أيمكن أنّك المتحرّي الشهير موري كوغورو-سان؟
Yes, that's me...
أجل، صحيح
Look! He's shaking hands with Masked Yaiba!
انظروا، العمّ يصافح يايبا المقنّع
No, I'm not the real Masked Yaiba.
كلا، لستُ يايبا المقنّع الحقيقيّ
Tsutsumi Yasuyuki (21) Jonan University, Law Dept.
(تسوتسومي ياسويوكي (21 كليّة الحقوق، جامعة جونان
I'm Tsutsumi Yasuyuki,
اسمي تسوتسومي ياسويوكي
and I'm a member of a college fan club.
وأنا عضوٌ في نادي معجبين شكّلناه في الجامعة
He's right! He isn't Masked Yaiba!
!إنّه محقّ! ليس يايبا المقنّع
Yes, the real one looks a lot more handsome.
الحقيقيّ أكثر وسامة
Sorry for disappointing you.
أعتذر على تخييب أملكم
Then that other person was also...
...إذاً ذاك الشخص كان أيضاً
Say! Want to come to a party?
بالمناسبة، أتريدون المشاركة في حفلة؟
Party?
حفلة؟
Our fan club is having a costume party!
،اجتمع رفاقي في نادي المعجبين ويقيمون حفلة تنكّر
Wow! That sounds like fun!
!يبدو ذلك مسليّاً
I'd love to go!
!أريد القدوم
Go! Go!
!فلتذهبوا
Now I won't have to pay for their food!
هكذا لن أدفع لطعامهم
You're invited too, Mori-san! There'll be beer, too!
،تفضّل بزيارتنا أيضاً يا موري-سان لدينا جعّة أيضاً
B-Beer?! I'd love to! I'd love to!
!جـ-جعّة؟ سآتي! سآتي
Now you won't have to pay for your beer!
ولن تدفع لجعّتك الآن كذلك
The party is in the basement of this mansion!
الحفلة مقامة في قبو هذا القصر
Look at all the monsters!
!يوجد الكثير من الوحوش
Even Monkeyshroom and Pork-n-Bones are here!
!حتّى قرد الخيزران والخنزير العظميّ موجودان هنا
The Mole Alien, too!
!فضائيّ الخلد أيضاً
Mori-san. Let me introduce you.
موري-سان، دعني أعرّفك عليها
This is our club's president, Saotome Madoka-san. This is her house.
إنّها رئيسة نادينا ومالكة القصر، ساوتومي مادوكا-سان
Are you a college student?
أأنتِ طالة جامعيّة؟
Yes! I'm in my third year studying literature!
أجل، أنا في سنتي الثالثة في كليّة الأدب
Saotome Madoka (21) Shirakaba Women's College
(ساوتومي مادوكا (21 جامعة شيراكابا للإناث
It's an honor to speak with the great Mori-san!
يشرّفني الكلام مع المتحرّي الشهير موري-سان
It's my pleasure!
!البتّة
I can recount my humble exploits anytime you want, day or night!
يمكنني أن أحكي لك قصصي !نهاراً وليلاً ومتى أردتِ
Do you know who she's dressed up as?
أتعرفون ما هو تنكّر تلك الآنسة؟
Yeah! Natsume Rei, right?
أجل، ناتسومي ري، أليس كذلك؟
Correct! You must tune in a lot!
تماماً! لا بدّ أنّكم تشاهدونه كثيراً
Have you ever watched Masked Yaiba, Mori-san?
أسبق وشاهدت يايبا المقنّع يا موري-سان؟
I'd really like to, but I'm so busy with work that time of day...
،حسناً، كنتُ أرغب في مشاهدته لكنّي مشغول بالعمل وقت عرضه دوماً
More like drinking that time of day...
بل مشغولٌ بالشرب وقتها
Masked Yaiba is really a young man who sells hot dogs at the park
يايبا المقنّع هو شاب عاديّ يبيع الهوت دوغ في الحديقة عادةً
with Natsume Rei, his childhood friend!
مع صديقة طفولته، ناتسومي ري
Each time an incident occurs, he rushes there on his motorcycle
كلّما تقع حادثة، يهرع إلى مسرحها بدرّاجته الناريّة
and fights the evil bad guys and aliens!
!ويقاتل الأشرار والمخلوقات الفضائيّة
But Natsume Rei doesn't know his secret identity!
لكنّ ناتسومي ري تجهل هويّة يايبا الحقيقيّة
So he's always ditching work to rush off on his motorcycle!
لذا يترك عمله دوماً ويذهب إلى مكانٍ ما بدرّاجته
Even so, Natsume Rei forgives him with gentle feelings!
ومع ذلك، تسامحه ناتسومي ري بكلّ رقّة
For some reason, I somehow know how that feels...
أتفهّم شعورها نوعاً ما
Come to think of it, that does sound kind of like me and Ran...
بالمناسبة، هذا الوضع يشبهني وران قليلاً
Okay, everyone! Let's go to the tables! We have some juice!
!حسناً يا صغار، لنذهب للطاولة هناك! توجد عصيرات
What about me, Madoka-san?
وأنا يا مادوكا-سان؟
She loves kids.
إنّها تحبّ الأطفال
Oh, I wish I could be a kid again!
حسناً، ليتني أرجع طفلاً
I wish I could be an adult again!
ليتني أرجع بالغاً
Hey there, Honda! You're late!
!مرحباً يا هوندا، تأخّرت
Yeah, sorry. It took longer than I thought.
أجل، آسف، طال الأمر قليلاً
Honda Osamu (21) Jonan Univ., Engineering Dept.
(هوندا أوسامو (21 كليّة الهندسة، جامعة جونان
He's that other guy. I guess he is a member of the fan club.
إنّه ذاك الشخص، كان عضواً في نادي المعجبين بالفعل إذاً
Huh? Why're you dressed like that?
...ماذا؟ زيّك هذا
I thought I'd change things up a bit.
خطر لي أن أغيّر أحياناً
What a shock. You've only ever dressed as Masked Yaiba before.
هذه صدمة، لم تتنكّر بعير زيّ يايبا المقنّع قبلاً
Oh, yeah! This is Mori Kogoro-san, the famous detective!
صحيح، هذا المتحرّي الشهير موري كوغورو-سان
M-Mori?
مـ-موري؟
He's Honda Osamu. He's in his third year of engineering at Jonan U.
إنّه هوندا أوسامو، طالب سنة ثالثة في كليّة الهندسة في جامعة جونان
He's only been in the club half a year,
لا يزال حديثاً في النادي، مضى على التحاقه ستّة أشهر
but he's a very passionate Masked Yaiba fan!
لكنّه أحد معجبي يايبا المقنّع الشغوفين جدّاً
That gun wouldn't happen to be real, would it?
مسدّسك هذا ليس حقيقيّاً، صحيح؟
Don't be silly! It's only a model! See for yourself!
!بالطبع لا! إنّه مقلّد! انظر بنفسك
I bet it's well-made! He's a real gun fanatic!
لا بدّ أنّه متقن الصنع، فهو مهووس بالمسدّسات
The texture and weight are impressive...
الملمس والوزن دقيقان، إنّه مُبهر
The bullets are all blanks. The barrel is plugged too, of course.
كلّ الطلقات فارغة، وأسطوانة المسدّس مسدودة بالطبع
Indeed.
بالفعل
Mori-san! Won't you come and tell us a story?
موري-سان! لمَ لا تأتي هنا وتحكي لنا قصّة؟
Yes, Madoka-san! Right away!
!أجل يا مادوكا-سان! من فوري
What a nice reply.
يا للردّ
Yes.
بالفعل
Come over to the tables, too!
رافقوني للطاولة أيضاً
Okay!
حسناً
Honda!
!هوندا
Mishima Katsuji (21) Toto University, P.E. Dept.
(ميشيما كاتسوجي (21 كليّة التربية البدنيّة، جامعة توتو
I've had enough! Get ready, Honda! I'm gonna kill you!
!لن أسامحك! تحضّر يا هوندا
Mishima-kun?!
!ميشيما-كن؟
W-Wait, Mishima! What did I ever do?!
تـ-تمهّل يا ميشيما؟ ما الذي فعلتُه؟
I can't stand you anymore!
!لم أعد أحتمل سخريتك
Calm down, Mishima! Let's talk it over!
!اهدأ يا ميشيما! لنتكلّم في الأمر
Shut up! Die!
!اخرس! مُت
Honda-kun!
!هوندا-كن
No!
!توقّف
Stop, Conan-kun!
!كلا يا كونان-كن
Mishima!
!ميشيما
What the hell?!
...يا للهول
What?!
ماذا؟
A bulletproof vest...
...سترة مضادة للرصاص
Wearing this saved me...
...كنتُ أرتديها، أنقذتني
Honda!
!هوندا
Honda-kun! Are you okay?!
هوندا-كن! أأنت بخير؟
Don't move!
لا تتحرّك
There's no burn mark on his temple!
لا آثار حرق على صدغه
Come to think of it, he kept the gun away from his head when he shot.
صحيح، كان يبعد المسدّس عن رأسه عندما أوشك على الانتحار
Why?
لمَ؟
The deceased is Mishima Katsuji-san, age 21.
المُتوفى هو ميشيما كاتسوجي-سان، 21 عاماً
A third year student at Toto U.'s physical education department.
طالب سنة ثالثة في كليّة التربية البدنيّة في جامعة توتو
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
This was a genuine suicide.
كان هذا انتحاراً حقيقيّاً
After all, we all witnessed it.
فقد شهدناه جميعاً بأنفسنا
Still... this is a rather odd sight...
مع ذلك، يا للمنظر الغريب
The Laser Police always wear these vests when fighting monsters,
كانت شرطة الليزر ترتدي هذه الستر المضادة للرصاص عند قتال الوحوش دوماً
so I bought one from a security store.
فذهبتُ لمتجر أمنيّ واشتريت واحدة
So, convinced he'd killed you,
وفي جهله لذلك، اعتقد ميزوشيما-سان
Mishima-san then shot himself in the head?
أنّه قتلك، فأطلق على رأسه بنفسه؟
But why would he try to kill you?
لكن لمَ كان يحاول قتلك؟
That's because...
...ذلك
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
Honda-kun and Mishima-kun were actually very good friends.
كان هوندا-كن وميشيما-كن صديقان مقرّبان كثيراً في الماضي
So what happened?
وما الذي حصل؟
About ten days ago, when we had gathered to plan this party,
قبل عشرة أيام تقريباً، عندما اجتمعنا هنا للتخطيط لهذه الحفلة
Mishima-kun got mad at an off-hand comment by Honda-kun
غضب ميشيما-كن من تعليقٍ صدر عبثاً من ميشيما-كن
and stormed out.
فغادر مسرعاً
What did you say to him?
وما الذي قلته له؟
I told him, "Your motorcycle is lame."
أخبرته أنّ درّاجته سخيفة
That's it?!
فقط ذلك؟
That's absurd! Nobody would be driven to murder because of that!
لا يُعقل! لا يمكن أن يُقدم أحد !على القتل لشيءٍ كهذا
No, it's not as crazy as it sounds.
كلا، الأمر ليس مستبعداً كما يظهر
He was especially obsessive about Masked Yaiba, even among us.
فقد كان ميشيما شديد الهوس بيايبا المقنّع حتّى بيننا
He spent half a year remodeling a normal motorcycle
أمضى قرابة نصف عام في تعديل درّاجة ناريّة عاديّة
into a Masked Yaiba motorcycle.
لتصبح درّاجة يايبا المقنّع
So I can understand why making fun of it would make him mad.
فأتفهّم غضبه من السخرية منها
I see...
...هكذا إذاً
I guess that's the only way to explain it.
لا تفسير غير هذا
His explanation seems truthful enough. But something bugs me!
،لا يبدو أنّهم يكذبون في توضيحهم لكن هناك ما يضايقني
There's something about this incident!
شيء في هذه الحادثة
Inspector Megure. The gun was a modified model gun.
مفتّش ميغوري، كان المسدّس مسدّس تقليد معدّل
The bullet in the bulletproof vest was also made by hand.
وكانت الرصاصة العالقة بالسترة المضادة للرصاص يدويّة الصنع أيضاً
Thank you.
شكراً لك
Was Mishima-san knowledgeable about guns at all?
أكان ميشيما-سان ملمّاً بالمسدّسات؟
I don't believe so.
لا أظن أنّه كان يعرف الكثير
He once asked me the difference between automatics and revolvers.
فقد سألني قبل فترة عن الفرق بين المسدّسات الآليّة والدوّارة
Come to think of it, do all Masked Yaiba members...?
...بالمناسبة، أكلّ أعضاء يايبا المقنّع
Hey, what characters in Masked Yaiba carry guns?
أخبروني، أيّ شخصيات تحمل مسدّسات في يايبا المقنّع؟
Only the Laser Police carry guns, duh!
من يحملون المسدّسات هم شرطة !الليزر فحسب بالطبع
Masked Yaiba himself doesn't?
لا يحمل يايبا المقنّع بنفسه مسدّساً؟
Conan-kun! Masked Yaiba has no need for guns!
!كونان-كن! لا يحتاج يايبا المقنّع لمسدّسات
He always fights with his bare hands!
!يقاتل بيديه العاريتين دوماً
I thought so!
كما ظننت
Still, that leaves too many things unclear...
لكن يترك ذلك أشياء كثيرة مبهمة
It sure is shocking to see something like this happen, though.
لكنّي صُدمت لوقوع شيءٍ كهذا أمام أعيننا
That's for sure. I guess TV dramas aren't entirely fiction after all.
بالفعل، يبدو أنّ الأحداث في الدراما قد تقّع على الواقع أحياناً
Dramas? Acting?
الدراما؟ تمثيل؟
All the mysteries connect now!
!اتّصلت كلّ الألغاز الآن
This was a murder!
!هذه قضيّة... جريمة قتل
If my theory is correct, it solves all the mysteries.
إذا أصاب استنتاجي، فستُحلّ كلّ الألغاز
Damn... Committing a murder right in front of me...
تبّاً... يرتكب جريمة قتل أمام ناظري
Unforgivable!
!لن أسامحه
Proof! I need to find undeniable proof!
الدليل، أنا بحاجة لدليلٍ دامغ
That's it! As I recall--!
...صحيح! آنذاك
Genta! Let me borrow your Detective League badge for a minute!
!غينتا! أعرني شارة فرقة التحرّي خاصّتك قليلاً
Huh? Mine?
ماذا؟ شارتي؟
Mori-san did?
قال موري-سان ذلك؟
Yeah... he asked me to get it examined right away. Says it's urgent.
أجل، طلب منّي أن أرسلها للفحص الفوريّ
Inspector, I'd like to take Honda to the hospital...
حضرة المفتّش، أودّ أخذ هوندا للمشفى
Oh, right.
صحيح
Even with the bulletproof vest on, he was shot from close range.
،حتّى لو كان يرتدي سترةً مضادة للرصاص فقد أُصيب برصاصة عن قرب
He could have a cracked rib. Let's drive him there right away.
،قد يعاني بضعة أضلاع مكسورة لنأخذه هناك بسيّارة شرطة
Huh? W-Why--?
ماذا؟
Not so fast, Inspector.
انتظر حضرة المفتّش
Please wait until later to take him to the hospital.
أجّل اصطحابه للمشفى من فضلك
What're you talking about, Mori-kun?
ما الذي تتكلّم عنه يا موري-كن؟
Didn't Mishima-san commit suicide?
ألم ينتحر ميشيما-سان؟
No... this was a bonafide murder.
كلا، كانت هذه جريمة قتل كليّة
Plotted by a certain someone from the start.
من تدبير أحدهم منذ البداية
Come again?!
ماذا؟
This someone suggested to Mishima-san
اقترح ذلك الشخص على ميشيما-سان
that they act out a little play to surprise everyone at the party.
أن يمثلا مسرحيةً صغيرة في الحفلة القادمة أمام الجميع لمفاجأتهم
Act?
يمثلا؟
In it, Mishima-san would pretend to shoot someone, then kill himself.
كانت أن يتظاهر ميشيما-سان بإطلاقه على شخصٍ ما، ثمّ ينتحر بعدها
To lay the groundwork for this, they had a fake argument beforehand.
لوضع أساس ذلك، تظاهرا بجدالٍ زائف أمام الجميع قبلاً
Yes... that someone was you, Honda Osamu-san!
صحيح، كان ذاك الشخص هو !أنت يا هوندا أوسامو-سان
What?
ما الذي تقوله؟
First, you modified two model guns of the same type
أوّلاً، عدّلت مسدّسين مقلّدين من الطراز نفسه
and prepared two types of bullets.
وحضّرت صنفين من الطلقات
One type was a real lead bullet. The other was an empty "blank."
،كان أحدهما رصاصات حقيقيّة بينما الآخر ذخيرة فارغة
You initially gave Mishima-san the gun with the blanks.
أعطيتَ ميشيما-سان المسدّس بالذخيرة الفارغة بدايةً
Today, before the party began, you met him at the Beika Shrine
قبل بداية الحفلة اليوم، التقيتَه في ضريح بيكا
and switched his gun with the gun with real bullets...
وبدّلت المسدّس ذو الذخيرة الفارغة بالآخر ذي الرصاصات الحقيقيّة الذي كان بحوزتك
Probably by saying you were doing final checks.
فعلتَ ذلك بقول أنّك تجري مراجعة نهائيّة غالباً
Then the gun on Honda-san's hip is Mishima-san's?!
المسدّس الذي على خصر هوندا-سان الآن هو مسدّس ميشيما-سان إذاً؟
No, wait. Wasn't the barrel of that gun plugged?
ماذا؟ لكن ألم تكن أسطوانة المسدّس الذي بحوزته مسدودة؟
Plus, the gun with real bullets wasn't plugged...
كما أنّ المسدّس ذو الرصاصات الحقيقيّة لم يكن مسدوداً
Wouldn't Mishima-san have noticed?
ألم يكن هنالك احتمال بملاحظة ميشيما-سان لذلك؟
No... the gun he handed Mishima-san wasn't plugged.
كلا، لم تكن أسطوانة المسدّس الذي أعطاه ميشيما-سان مسدودة
He plugged it after the switch,
قام بسدّها بعد التبديل
so he wouldn't rouse suspicion after the fact.
كيلا يثير الشبهة بعد الحادثة
Honda-san dressed up as a Laser Police member
تنكُّر هوندا-سان كفرد من شرطة الليزر اليوم
instead of his usual choice of Masked Yaiba
بدل تنكّره المعتاد كيايبا المقنّع
because it wouldn't seem strange for a Laser Police member
كان لأنّ حمل أعضاء شرطة الليزر لمسدّس
to carry a gun and wear a bulletproof vest.
أو ارتداء سترة مضادة للرصاص لن يكون غريباً في حالتهم فقط
When Mishima-san jumped down,
عندما قفز ميشيما-سان
you moved as if taking us out of harm's way,
تحرّكت بحيث يبدو أنّك تبعدنا عن الخطر
but it was actually to make you an easier target for him.
لكن كان ذلك لتجعل نفسك هدفاً أسهل لـ ميشيما-سان
B-But, Mori-san!
،لـ-لكن يا موري-سان
Wouldn't Mishima know something was up if a real bullet came out?
ألن يلاحظ ميشيما وجود أمرٍ غريب إذا انطلقت رصاصات حقيقيّة؟
He and Honda-san had probably done rehearsals
قام مع هوندا-سان بتمارين سابقة غالباً
in which he would pretend to be hit the same time the gun sounded.
بحيث تظاهر بإصابته مع صدور صوت الإطلاق
So, after seeing Honda-san being "hit" this time,
لذا بعد رؤيته لإصابة هوندا-سان فعلياً هذه المرة
Mishima-san believed it was just like it was during rehearsal.
اعتقد ميشيما-سان أنّ الأمر مماثل لتمارينهما
It's your so-called "autosuggestion."
ما يُعرف بالإحياء الذاتي
But do you have any evidence that he didn't commit suicide?
لكن، أيوجد دليلٌ على أنّ ميشيما-كن لم ينتحر؟
If you were to kill yourself by putting a gun to your head and firing,
من يريد الانتحار حقّاً، ستبقى على رأسه آثار احتراق
burn marks would be left on your head.
عندما يلصق فوهة المسدّس به
However, there were none on Mishima-san.
لكن لم تكن هنالك آثار على ميشيما-سان
Even with blanks, it still produces a small flame.
حتّى بالذخيرة الفارغة، ستصدر شعلة
Which is why he held the gun slightly away from his head,
لذا أبعد المسدّس عن رأسه قليلاً
to prevent being burned.
كيلا يحترق
You can't be sure about that! He was a weird guy!
!لا يمكنكم الجزم بذلك! فقد كان ميشيما غريب أطوار
Then allow me to show you some proof.
دعوني أقدّم الدليل لكم إذاً
Examiner!
حضرة المحلّل
Another set of fingerprints not belonging to the late Mishima-san
الـ-المعذرة، وجدنا بصمات أخرى لا تخصّ ميشيما-سان الميت
was found on this gun.
على هذا المسدّس
They also match the child's fingerprints on this badge.
إنّها تطابق البصمات على شارة الطفل أيضاً
That's Genta-kun's!
!إنّها لغينتا-كن
Which means...
...إ-إذاً
...I'm the killer?
أنا القاتل؟
Genta-kun! When did you touch Mishima-san's gun?!
غينتا-كن! متى لمستَ مسدّس ميشيما-سان؟
I-I didn't!
!لـ-لم ألمسه
Yes.
صحيح
If Genta didn't touch Mishima-san's gun, how did his prints get on it?
،لو لم يلمس غينتا مسدّس ميشيما-سان فلمَ بصماته عليه؟
The answer to that is... Conan!
!للإجابة على ذلك، كونان
Right!
حاضر
Honda-san.
هوندا-سان
You ran into us at the Beika Shrine before coming here, right?
صادفتنا في ضريح بيكا قبل قدومك إلى هنا، أليس كذلك؟
And then Genta...
...قام غينتا وقتها
This gun's so cool!
!هذا المسدّس رائع
Don't touch that!
!لا تلمسه
H-He touched it then?
لـ-لمسه آنذاك؟
The fact you had Mishima-san's gun then
كون المسدّس الذي كان معك هو مسدّس ميشيما-سان
is evidence that you switched your guns later!
!دليلٌ على تبديلك للمسدّسين لاحقاً
Honda-kun...
...هوندا-كن
Mori-san. When did you start to suspect me?
موري-سان، متى بدأت الاشتباه بي؟
Tsutsumi-san said that you were a real gun aficionado.
أخبرني تسوتسومي-سان أنّك كنت مهووساً بالمسدّسات
Yet, you had a plugged gun. That seemed odd to me.
،مع ذلك، سددت أسطوانة مسدّس وذلك ما أثار غرابتي
I see. Plugging the gun to be extra safe proved to be my downfall...
فهمت، سدّي للمسدّس لتوخّي الحذر أدّى لهلاكي
Mishima... killed my kid brother!
...قتلت ميشيما
Two years ago, my brother Hiroshi was heading to a friend's house
قبل عامين، كان أخي الصغير هيروشي متوجّهاً لمنزل صديق
To Hiroshi-kun
بلوحة بتوقيع يايبا المقنّع
Wait! Give it back!
!انتظر! أعدها لي
Hiroshi died two days later.
مات هيروشي بعدها بيومين
His final words were, "Get Masked Yaiba to catch him..."
"كانت آخر كلماته "اجعل يايبا المقنّع يمسك به
I joined a number of Masked Yaiba fan clubs to gather information
انضممتُ لعددٍ من أندية معجبي يايبا المقنّع لجمع معلومات
and figure out who stole it!
واكتشاف هويّة السارق
Then, half a year ago...
...ثمّ قبل 6 أشهر
...Mishima finally showed me that signboard!
!أراني ميشيما تلك اللوحة أخيراً
He said his older brother had won it and given it to him!
ادّعى أنّ أخاه الكبير فاز بها وأعطاه إيّاها
But he doesn't have a brother named Hiroshi!
!لكن لم يكن لديه أخٌ يُدعى هيروشي
So then you got your revenge on him?
لذا انتقمتَ منه؟
Inspector, it's not discussed in the TV drama,
،حضرة المفتّش، لا يظهر هذا في الدراما التلفزيّة
but Masked Yaiba has a back story in which his sister was killed.
لكن ليايبا المقنّع قصّة خلفيّة قُتلت فيها شقيقته الصغيرة
I joined fan clubs to kill the person who drove my brother to death,
انضممتُ لأندية المعجبين لقتل الشخص الذي سرق لوحة هيروشي وقاده لموته
but at some point, I began to feel just like Masked Yaiba.
لكن في مرحلةٍ ما، بدأت أشعر أنّي مشابه ليايبا المقنّع
You and Masked Yaiba are nothing alike!
!لا شبه بينك وبين يايبا المقنّع أبداً
Masked Yaiba doesn't fight for revenge!
!لا يقاتل يايبا المقنّع للانتقام
Yeah! He fights for justice!
!صحيح! إنّه يقاتل للعدالة
Yes, the children are right.
أجل، الأطفال محقّون
It's a shame you were that wrong about Masked Yaiba all along.
من المؤسف أنّك كنت مخطئاً في فهم يايبا المقنّع هكذا
Oh! Yoko-chan's on a music show starting at 7:30!
ستظهر يوكو-تشان في برنامج غنائيّ !في السابعة والنصف هذه الليلة
Oh, but we're watching Masked Yaiba at 7:30.
لكن لا يمكنك، سنشاهد يايبا المقنّع عند السابعة والنصف
What?! We never watch that junk!
!ماذا؟! لا نشاهده في العادة
We decided to watch it starting tonight!
قرّرنا البدء بمشاهدته من الليلة
After all, Masked Yaiba fights for justice! We gotta support him!
فيايبا المقنّع يقاتل الأشرار !لأجل العدالة! علينا دعمه
Right, Conan-kun?
أليس كذلك يا كونان-كن؟
Don't be stupid! What about Yoko-chan?!
...يا حمقاء! يوكو-تشان أيضاً
What about her?
يوكو-تشان أيضاً؟
S-She's sings for me!
!إ-إنّها تغنّي لأجلي
This old guy's gonna live a long life...
...سيعيش هذا المُسنّ حياةً طويلة
T-That was President Yamazaki!
!كـ-كانت تلك الرئيسة يامازاكي
What's this sticky stuff?!
ما هذا الشيء الدبق؟
So it was a completely locked room...
أي كانت الغرفة مقفلةً بالكامل
This might not have been an accident!
ربما لم تكن هذه حادثة
It's possible it was a murder plotted by one of these people!
من المحتمل أنّها جريمة قتل من تخطيط !أحد الأشخاص في الداخل
On the next Conan--
جريمة قتل كوكتيل العسل
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Balloon.
بالون
Next episode's case tastes like honey.
تحمل الحلقة القادمة (نكهة العسل! (هاتشيميتسو
Sweetie!
هاتشي: 8    ميتسو: 3
What? Why?
ماذا؟ لمَ؟
Didn't you call me honey?
ثمانية ضرب ثلاثة، صحيح؟